<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rfc xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" category="info" docName="draft-levine-dbound-dns-07" ipr="trust200902" obsoletes="" updates="" submissionType="IETF" xml:lang="en" tocInclude="true" tocDepth="2" symRefs="true" sortRefs="true" version="3">
  <front>
    <title abbrev="Org Boundaries">
	Publishing Organization Boundaries in the DNS
    </title>
    <author fullname="John Levine" initials="J." surname="Levine">
      <organization>Taughannock Networks</organization>
      <address>
        <email>standards@taugh.com</email>
        <uri>https://jl.ly</uri>
      </address>
    </author>
    <date year="2022"/>
    <area>Applications</area>
    <keyword>DNS</keyword>
    <keyword>cookies</keyword>
    <keyword>e-mail</keyword>
    <abstract>
      <t>The organization that manages a subtree in the DNS is often different
         from the one that manages the tree above it.  We describe an architecture to publish in the DNS
         the boundaries between organizations that can be adapted to various
         policy models and can be queried with a small number of DNS lookups.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <middle>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Introduction</name>
      <t>Often, the organization that manages a subtree in the DNS is
           different from the one that manages the tree above it.
	   Many applications use information about such boundaries to
           implement security policies.  For example, web browsers use them
           to limit the names where HTTP cookies can be set, and
	   Secure Socket Layer (SSL) certificate services use them to determine
           the party responsible for the domain in a signing request.
	   Mail security applications such as Domain-based Messaging
           Authentication, Reporting and Conformance (DMARC) use them to locate
	   an organization's policy records in the DNS.
	   This specification is intended to provide boundaries usable for DMARC,
	   and possibly for other applications.
      </t>
      <t>
	[[Please direct discussion of this draft to the dbound mailing list
	at dbound@ietf.org.]]
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Design Issues</name>
      <t>Organization boundaries can be assigned on what one could
	   call an opt-in or opt-out basis. "Opt-in" means that two names are only
	   managed by the same organization if both actively assert that they are
	   related.  "Opt-out" means that if there is any boundary information at
           all for a DNS subtree, each name is assumed to be under the same
           management as its parent unless there is a boundary assertion to the
           contrary.  This design describes an opt-out model.</t>
      <t>Within the opt-out model, this design can adapt to a variety of
           scenarios:
      </t>
      <ul spacing="normal">
        <li>Policies can be published by the domains themselves,
			    or by a third party.  In the former case, each domain
			    might assert its own boundary policies.  In the latter
			    case, the third party makes the assertions, which may
			    or may not agree with what the domains themselves
 			    would want.</li>
        <li>Multiple levels of delegation may be implemented,
			    which is different from irregular boundaries.  For
			    example, "us", "ny.us", and "k12.ny.us" are
			    irregular boundaries, because they're all handled by
			    the US top-level domain registry operator.
			    CentralNIC's "uk.com" would be a second level of
			    delegation below Verisign's com. </li>
        <li>Different sets of boundary rules can be published for
			    different applications.  For example, the boundaries
			    for SSL certificates might be different from the
			    boundaries for e-mail policies, or for HTTP cookie
			    setting policies.</li>
      </ul>
      <t>In the lookup process below, the boundary point data is stored in
	   the DNS tree in a TXT record.
	   The boundary is considered to be directly below the name that the
	   process returns, similarly to the names in the <xref target="PSL" format="default">PSL</xref>.
	   If the process returned "abc.example", then "foo.abc.example" and
	   "bar.abc.example" are separated by the boundary, but "foo.abc.example"
	   and "bar.foo.abc.example" are not.
      </t>
      <t>Each domain can publish its own policies within its own domain name space,
	      or a separate authority can publish a global set of policies in a separate
	      name space.
      </t>
      <section><name>Non-goals</name>
	 <t>
	    This specification is intended only to describe vertical relationships
	    between domain names and their ancestors or descendants.
	    For example, if there is a boundary between "com" and "example.com", but
	    no boundary between "example.com" and "www.example.com", that indicates
	    that "com" is one organization, while "example.com" and "www.example.com"
	    are a different organization.
	 </t>
	 <t>
	    While it may well be useful to indicate that "example.com" and "example.net"
	    are the same organization, this specification provides no way to describe
	    horizontal or cross-tree relationships.
	 </t>
	 <t>
	    This specification deliberately says nothing about zone cuts or zone boundaries.
	    While some zone cuts may match organization boundaries, it is quite common to have
	    multiple zones within an organization for administrative convenience, or for a hosting
	    provider to put the names of many customers' hosts in a single zone.
	 </t>
    </section>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>TXT record format</name>
      <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
  *._bound.k12.ny.us IN TXT bound=1 . . k12.ny.us]]></artwork>
      <t>
	   The bound TXT record contains at least four text strings: a tag, two keyword strings and a
	   domain name. Strings beyond the fourth are ignored.
	   Unlike in some other specification, the string boundaries are signficant.
      </t>
      <t>
	   The "bound=1" tag is to prevent confusion when a domain publishes a
	   wildcard such as *.example.com that could match a _bound name. Records
	   that do not start with the correct tag or that have fewer than four strings
	   are ignored.
      </t>
      <t>
	   Each keyword string is a series of comma separated keywords.
	   If the string would otherwise be empty, it is a single dot.
      </t>
      <t>
	   The first keyword string expresses policy options.
	   It can include NOLOWER which means that
	   no lower level boundaries can exist below this one, and NOBOUND
	   which means that this name is not a boundary for this application.
      </t>
      <t>
	   The second keyword string identifies the application(s) to
	   which this boundary applies.
	   The strings DMARC, COOKIE, and CERT mean that the applications are DMARC,
	   HTTP cookies, and SSL certificate signing respectively; a dot means it
	   is a default for any applications not otherwise specified.
      </t>
      <t>
	   The domain name is an absolute domain name, without the final dot.
	   The first label in the name may be "*" to indicate that the boundary is
	   at any name one label deeper than the rest of the name.  That is, the
	   asterisk matches a single label, not the usual DNS sense of matching
	   any string of labels.
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Lookup Process</name>
      <t>In general, the lookup process takes as input a domain name and application.
	   It returns the name of the boundary node in the DNS.
	   This may be the domain itself or a parent.
	   If there is no policy for the domain the lookup fails; there are no
           defaults, and the DNS root is not within any organization boundary.
	   (Applications may apply defaults of their own, but that is beyond the
           scope of this specification.)</t>
      <t>Names of boundary information records
	use the tag "_bound" which is intended to be unique.
      </t>
      <t>For the first lookup, the client extracts the top level component
           (i.e., the rightmost label, as "label" is defined in Section 3 of
           <xref target="RFC1034" format="default"/>)
           of the domain name from the subcomponents, if any, and inserts the
           prefix in front of that component, after other components if any.
	   For example, if the domain to be checked is "example.com" or
           "www.example.com", the client issues a DNS query for "example._bound.com"
	   or "www.example._bound.com".
	   If the domain is a dotless one such as "example", the client looks up "_bound.example".
      </t>
      <t>If the boundary information is published by a third party,
	 the client appends the base name of the
	 third party's domain to the name to be looked up.
	 Then the client does a DNS lookup of TXT records at that name,
	   which will return zero or more TXT records.
	   A failure such as NXDOMAIN is considered to return zero records.
	   A lookup can return multiple records if different applications have
	   different boundaries or policy options.
	   The lookup process discards any records that do not start with "bound=1"
	   or contain less than four strings.
      </t>
      <t>
	   If a relevant policy record is returned, and the record does not contain
	   the NOBOUND keyword, the domain name in
	   the record is the policy boundary.
	   A policy record is relevant if it lists the desired application, or
	   it is a default policy and there is no record with the application's keyword.
	   For example, a check for a boundary
           above "example.com" would be issued at "example._bound.com", and the
           expected TXT record could be "bound=1 . . com".</t>
      <t>If there are no boundaries at all in a TLD, the policy record
           contains "bound=1 .  . ." indicating the root.  For example, if all subdomains
           of the "example" top-level domain (TLD) are under the same management
           as the TLD itself, checks for "_bound.example" or "www._bound.example"
	   would return "bound=1 . . .". </t>
      <t>If the relevant record has the NOLOWER keyword set, the process stops.
	   Otherwise, the
	   client inserts the prefix tag into the name just below
           (i.e., to the left of) the name at the largest matching boundary
           indicated in the lookup result, and repeats the lookup.  For example:
      </t>
      <ul spacing="normal">
        <li> When evaluating "www.foo.example.com", the first query
                    would be to "www.foo.example._bound.com".  If the reply to this is
		    "bound=1 . . com",
                    then the second query would be to "www.foo._bound.example.com".
	</li>
        <li> When evaluating "www.example.ny.us", the first query would be
                    to "www.example.ny._bound.us".  If the reply to this is
                    "bound=1" . . us", the next lookup would be to
                    "www.example._bound.ny.us".
		    If it returned "bound=1 . . ny.us", the third lookup
		    would be to "www._bound.foo.ny.us".
	</li>
      </ul>
      <t>This process repeats until a DNS lookup returns a relevant record with
	   the NOLOWER keyword, or a lookup returns no relevant records,
           at which point the boundary is the domain name in the
	   last retrieved relevant record.</t>
      <t>If an otherwise relevant record has the NOBOUND keyword, the process
	   continues if the NOLOWER keyword is not present, but there is no boundary
	   at the name with the NOBOUND keyword.
	   The NOBOUND keyword enables a name in the hierarchy to be a boundary for some
	   applications but not for others.
      </t>
      <t>
	 If the domain name in a boundary record starts with a *, e.g., "*.example", the client
	 replaces the * with the corresponding element of the domain being matched.  If
	 the domain were "www.test.example", the boundary record domain would be treated as
	 though it were "test.example".
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>DNS Records</name>
      <t>The publishing entity uses wildcards and prefixed names that parallel the regular
           names under a TLD to cover the domain's name space.</t>
      <t>If there is a boundary at a given name, an entry in the TLD record
        covers the names below it.  For example, if there is a boundary
	at ".TEST", a suitable record would be:</t>
      <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
  *._bound.test IN TXT bound=1 . . test]]></artwork>
      <t> If the boundary is above the TEST domain, i.e., TEST is under the same
         management as FOO.TEST, the record would indicate no boundaries, and an
	 additional non-wildcard record is needed to cover TEST itself:</t>
      <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
  *._bound.test IN TXT bound=1 . . .
  _bound.test   IN TXT bound=1 . . .]]></artwork>
      <t> In domains with irregular policy boundaries, multiple records in the
          record describe the boundary points.  For example, in the US (United States)
          TLD, there are legacy domains under XX.US where XX is a two-letter
	  state abbreviation, and there are some further points such as "k12" for
	  schools within a state, with a boundary such as
          such as "k12.ny.us".  A suitable set of of records can cover
          this structure.
	  The closest encloser rule in <xref target="RFC4592" format="default">RFC 4592</xref> makes
	  the wildcards match the appropriate names.
      </t>
      <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
*._bound.us            IN TXT bound=1 . . us
*._bound.ny.us         IN TXT bound=1 . . ny.us
*._bound.k12.ny.us     IN TXT bound=1 . . k12.ny.us]]></artwork>
      <t>In the usual case that only the boundary closest to the looked up domain name
	 is of interest, the publishing entity can publish "shadow" wildcard records
	 for lower level boundaries 
	 that are used rather than the higher level records for names below those boundaries:
      </t>
	       <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
*.ny._bound.us         IN TXT bound=1 . . ny.us
*.k12.ny._bound.us     IN TXT bound=1 . . k12.ny.us]]></artwork>

   <t>[TBD: What if anything to put at the shadow point?  Currently if you look up
      "k12.ny._bound.us" you'll get nothing because it's an ENT.  Or should it always give an
       answer, in this case point to k12.ny.us? ]
   </t>

   <t>In some cases, a domain may assert that every name below a given name is
	   a boundary, or that every name other than a specific set of exceptions is
	   a boundary.  For example (adapted from the Mozilla PSL) every name below
	   kobe.jp is a boundary other than city.kobe.jp.  This could be expressed as:
      </t>
      <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
*.kobe._bound.jp       IN TXT bound=1 . . *.kobe.jp
city.kobe._bound.jp    IN TXT bound=1 NOBOUND . city.kobe.jp
*.city.kobe._bound.jp  IN TXT bound=1 NOBOUND . city.kobe.jp]]></artwork>
<t>Remember that the *.kobe.jp in the TXT record matches only a single
   label, so in a lookup for aaa.bbb.kobe.jp, the boundary is bbb.kobe.jp.</t>
      <t> For any set of policy boundaries in a tree of DNS names,
	 a suitable set of policy records can describe the boundaries,
	 so a client can find the boundary for any name in the tree with a
         single policy lookup per level of delegation. </t>
      <t> Since the delegation structure is unlikely to change 
          frequently, long time-to-live (TTL) values in the TXT
	  records are appropriate.</t>
      <t>
	  If different applications have different boundaries or policy options,
	  the policy records
	  for each application are put at the appropriate names for the boundaries.
a	  Due to the way DNS wildcards work, each name with any policy records <bcp14>MUST</bcp14>
	  have records for all policies, with the NOBOUND bit for policies for which
	  the name is not in fact a boundary.
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Application scenarios</name>
      <t>Here are some ways that DMARC and potentially other applications can use BOUND data.</t>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>DMARC</name>
        <t>If a DMARC lookup for the domain in a message's From: header fails,
	      the client would do a boundary check for the domain name using
	      the "DMARC" application.
	      The organizational domain is the immediate subdomain of the boundary
	      domain.  (Note that the boundary will always be the one looked up
	      or an ancestor.)
        </t>
      </section>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>Cookies</name>
        <t>If an http request attempts to set a cookie for a domain other
	      than the request's own domain, the client would do boundary check
	      for a "cookie" application for both the request's domain and the cookie
	      domain. If they are not separated by a boundary, the request is allowed.
        </t>
      </section>
      <section numbered="true" toc="default">
        <name>SSL Certificates</name>
        <t>The client would do a boundary check for the domain name in a
	      normal certificate, or the name after the "*." in a wildcard
	      certificate for a "cert" application.
	      If the boundary is above the name, the name is allowed.
        </t>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Discussion</name>
      <t>The total number of DNS lookups is no more than the number of levels of boundary
	   delegation, plus one if the last boundary doesn't have the NOLOWER keyword.
	   That is unlikely to be more than 2 or 3 in realistic scenarios, and
	   depends on the number of boundaries, not the number of components in
	   the names that are looked up.
	   With shadow records, it will typically be one lookup that matches a shadow record
	   and a second to check below it that gets NXDOMAIN if the shadow record doesn't
	   contain NOLOWER.
      </t>
      <t>Some domains have very irregular boundaries.
	 This may require a relatively large number of records to describe all the boundaries,
	 but it doesn't seem like a number that would challenge
	 modern DNS servers, or need unduly complex scripts to create them.
n	 A mechanical translation of the boundary information the Mozilla PSL as of August 2022
	 creates about 17,000 records.
      </t>
      <t>The wildcard lookup means that each time an application looks up the boundaries
	 for a hostname, the lookup results create DNS cache entries that will not be reused
	 other than for subsequent lookups for the identical hostname.
	 This might cause cache churn, but it seems at worst no more than we already
	 tolerate from DNSBL lookups.
	 If the boundary zone is signed, DNS caches should be able to syntheize some answers
	 from cached wildcards.
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>ABNF syntax of bound records</name>
      <t>The syntax of bound records is something like this:
      </t>
      <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
; each token in BOUND is a separate string in the TXT record

BOUND = BTAG BFLAGS BKWDS DOMAIN

BTAG = %s"bound=1"

BFLAGS = ( BFLAG *("," BFLAG) ) / "."

BFLAG = s%"NOLOWER" / s%"NOBOUND" / MISCTOK

BKWDS = ( BKWD *("," BKWD) ) / "."

BKWD  = s%"DMARC" / s%"COOKIE" / s%"CERT" / MISCTOK

; miscellaneous tokens for future expansion

MISCTOK = `1*ALPHA]]></artwork>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Security Considerations</name>
      <t>The purpose of publishing organization boundaries is to provide
           advice to third parties that wish to know whether two names are
           managed by the same organization, allowing those names to 
	   be treated "as the same" in some sense.  Clients that rely on
           published boundaries are outsourcing some part of their own
	   security policy to the publisher, so their own security depends on
           the publisher's boundaries being accurate. </t>
      <t>Although in some sense domains are always in control of their
           subdomains, there are many situations in which parent domains are
           not expected to influence subdomains.  For example, second
	   level domains in
	   global TLDs (gTLDs) operated by registries with contracts with
	   the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numers (ICANN)
	   Since there is no technical bar to a parent publishing records
           that shadow part or all of the boundary record namespace for
           delegated subdomains, correct operation depends on
	   the parent and subdomains agreeing about who publishes what. </t>
      <t>The DNS is subject to a variety of attacks. DBOUND records
	   are subject to the same ones as any other bit of the DNS, and
	   the same countermeasures, such as using DNSSEC, apply.
      </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Variations</name>
      <t>
	   Some boundary schemes distinguish between public and private subtrees.
	   If that were useful, a PUBLIC flag keyword could indicate that the subtrees
	   below a boundary were public rather than the default of private.
      </t>
      <t>Since nothing but the boundary records should be published at names with _bound
	   components, one could get the same effect with a new DBOUND RRTYPE, which would
	   avoid the problem of confusion with other TXT wildcards.
	   Its syntax would be the same as a TXT record, a series of text strings, but without the initial
	   tag field.
	   They would still need to be in a separate subtree identified by _bound labels so that
	   the wildcard name coverage would work.
      </t>
      <t>If third parties want to publish boundary information, they can
	   do it in their own subtree of the DNS. For example,
	   if policy.example were publishing boundary information about
	   boundaries, the records for the test domain described above would be:
      </t>
      <artwork name="" type="" align="left" alt=""><![CDATA[
  *._bound.test.policy.exaple IN TXT bound=1 . . .
  _bound.test.policy.example  IN TXT bound=1 . . .]]></artwork>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>IANA considerations</name>
      <t>IANA is requested to add this entry to the
	  "Underscored and Globally Scoped DNS Node Names" Registry.
      </t>
      <table anchor="boundtagreg" align="center">
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th align="center">RR Type</th>
            <th align="left">_NODE NAME</th>
            <th align="left">Reference</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td align="center">TXT</td>
            <td align="left">_bound</td>
            <td align="left">(this document)</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <t>This document requests that IANA create a registry of dbound Flag keywords.
	 Its registration policy is IETF Review.
	 Its initial contents are as follows.
      [[NOTE: new flags are likely to change the lookup algorithm]]</t>
      <table anchor="boundflagreg" align="center">
        <name>BOUND Flag Keywords Initial Values</name>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th align="center">Keyword</th>
            <th align="left">Reference</th>
            <th align="left">Description</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td align="center">NOLOWER</td>
            <td align="left">(this document)</td>
            <td align="left">No lower level policies</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td align="center">NOBOUND</td>
            <td align="left">(this document)</td>
            <td align="left">No boundary at this name</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
      <t>This document requests that IANA create a registry of BOUND Application keywords.
	 Its registration policy is First Come First Served.
	 Its initial contents are as follows.
      [[Note: New applications don't affect the lookup process, and shouldn't
      affect existing applications.]]</t>
      <table anchor="boundappreg" align="center">
        <name>BOUND Applications Initial Values</name>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <th align="center">Value</th>
            <th align="left">Reference</th>
            <th align="left">Description</th>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td align="center">. (Any)</td>
            <td align="left">(this document)</td>
            <td align="left">Any application without a specific boundary record</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td align="center">DMARC</td>
            <td align="left">(this document)</td>
            <td align="left">DMARC organizational domains</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td align="center">COOKIE</td>
            <td align="left">(this document)</td>
            <td align="left">HTTP cookies</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td align="center">CERT</td>
            <td align="left">(this document)</td>
            <td align="left">Owner of certificate requests</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </section>
  </middle>
  <back>
    <references>
      <name>References</name>
      <references>
        <name>Normative References</name>
        <reference anchor="RFC1034" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc1034" xml:base="https://www.rfc-editor.org/refs/bibxml/reference.RFC.1034.xml">
          <front>
            <title>Domain names - concepts and facilities</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC1034"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="1034"/>
            <seriesInfo name="STD" value="13"/>
            <author initials="P.V." surname="Mockapetris" fullname="P.V. Mockapetris">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="1987" month="November"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This RFC is the revised basic definition of The Domain Name System.  It obsoletes RFC-882.  This memo describes the domain style names and their used for host address look up and electronic mail forwarding.  It discusses the clients and servers in the domain name system and the protocol used between them.</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
        <reference anchor="RFC4592" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc4592" xml:base="https://www.rfc-editor.org/refs/bibxml/reference.RFC.4592.xml">
          <front>
            <title>The Role of Wildcards in the Domain Name System</title>
            <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC4592"/>
            <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="4592"/>
            <author initials="E." surname="Lewis" fullname="E. Lewis">
              <organization/>
            </author>
            <date year="2006" month="July"/>
            <abstract>
              <t>This is an update to the wildcard definition of RFC 1034.  The interaction with wildcards and CNAME is changed, an error condition is removed, and the words defining some concepts central to wildcards are changed.  The overall goal is not to change wildcards, but to refine the definition of RFC 1034.  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
            </abstract>
          </front>
        </reference>
      </references>
      <references>
        <name>Informative References</name>
        <reference anchor="PSL" target="https://publicsuffix.org/">
          <front>
            <title>Public Suffix List</title>
            <author>
              <organization>Mozilla Foundation</organization>
            </author>
          </front>
        </reference>
      </references>
    </references>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
       <name>Implementations</name>
       <t>
	  A sample python implementation is available at
	  https://github.com/jrlevine/bound.
	  It includes a library routine to find the boundaries for a domain name,
	  and a script to translate the <xref target="PSL">Mozilla PSL</xref> into
	  the DNS format.
	  For testing, a copy of the translated PSL is online at bound.services.net.
       </t>
    </section>
    <section numbered="true" toc="default">
      <name>Change Log</name>
      <t><strong>NOTE TO RFC EDITOR: This section may be removed
	   upon publication of this document as an RFC.</strong></t>
      <dl newline="false" spacing="normal">
        <dt>06 to -07</dt>
        <dd>Clean up quoting in examples</dd>
        <dt>05 to -06</dt>
        <dd>Editorial changes, add non-goals</dd>
        <dt>04 to -05</dt>
        <dd>Editorial changes, add implementation appendix
		</dd>
        <dt>03 to -04</dt>
        <dd>Make TXT fields separate strings, add shadow records, update ABND
		</dd>
        <dt>02 to -03</dt>
        <dd>Add wildcard labels like in the PSL.
		</dd>
        <dt>01 to -02</dt>
        <dd>Make TXT record the proposal, new RR as alternative.
	     </dd>
        <dt>-00 to -01</dt>
        <dd>Editorial changes to limit standard use to DMARC.
	   </dd>
        <dt>non-WG to -00</dt>
        <dd>Add NOBOUND record to make wildcard matches do the right thing</dd>
        <dt/>
        <dd>Rename to match WG name</dd>
      </dl>
    </section>
  </back>
</rfc>
